# 豆腐白菜丸子 这菜有食欲
Tofu, cabbage, (meat) balls, this dish looks appetizing
# 四季平安 大烩菜
Wish you safe (well) in all four seasons. Big Stew Dish.
# 这全乎 还有肉片呢
This has all, look there is sliced pork
# 有什么原料就搁什么原料
Put whatever ingredients you have
# 煸一下肉片
Stir the meat slices
# 肉片要厚点 五花肉片
The slice pork needs to be thicker, sliced pork belly
# 这个一般就是大锅炖
Usually we would use a big pot to stew
# 冬天来这么一锅
Imaging having such a big stew in winter time
# 大料瓣  葱丁下上
Star anise, spring onion in
# 炸成金黄色
Fried into golden brown
# 这菜有点意思
This dish is interesting
# 蒜跟姜搁进去
Put garlic and ginger in
# 四季平安菜 白菜豆腐保平安
Four Seasons Ping An Vegetables, Chinese Cabbage and Tofu keeps you safe
# 看着那肉就有食欲
Look at the meat it’s so alluring
# 这块儿这厚度适合我 不能太薄
This piece is suitable for me, not too thin
# 把这黄花搁进去一块煸一下
Put this (dried) yellow flower in and stir it together
# 提鲜又提香
Fresh and fragrant
# 忘忧草啊 吃着高兴啊
Worry-less grass, eat and feel the joy
# 木耳 把水一定挤干了
To cook the fungus you must squeeze the water throughly
# 西红柿借点味 借点鲜味
Borrow some umami flavor from tomatoes
# 香味出来了 你看他煸菜的流程对
The smell comes out. Look at his cooking process, right
# 这时候咱们就顺着锅边烹酱油
At this time, let's cook soy sauce along the side of the pot
# 你看到没有 这不贴着锅边
Did you see it? If you don’t pour soy sauce along the side of the pot
# 香味出不来 锅气出不来
The aroma won’t come out, wok-hei won't come out
# 顺序有讲究 先煸肉片煸出香味来
The order is exquisite, first stir the meat slices to get the aroma
# 然后再煸大料 让料香味出来
Then stir the star anise to let the flavor come out
# 然后跟着葱姜蒜 黄花木耳西红柿
Then followed with green onion, ginger, garlic, yellow flower, fungus, tomatoes
# 加水 开水
Add water, boiling water
# 红薯粉条来一大锅 这好吃
Add a big portion of sweet potato noodle, it's delicious
# 还不够吃这个
Not enough to eat
# 再来点水 这点就差不多了
Some more water, that's about it
# 这边炖上 炸点丸子
Simmer here, fry some meatballs
# 开大火
Turn on the heat
# 这丸子馅里头有
This meatball has
# 肉馅姜末小葱末
Minced ginger and shallot
# 糯米蒸熟的 鸡蛋黄一个鸡蛋黄
Steamed glutinous rice with egg yolk and one egg yolk
# 蛋清也可以
Egg white is fine too
# 盐 胡椒粉 酱油
Salt pepper soy sauce
# 这丸子有时候我们家也自己做
Sometimes our family makes this meatball by ourselves
# 香油是吧 香油这儿呢
Sesame oil, right? sesame oil here
# 老岳母是安徽的
My mother-in-law is from Anhui
# 她每年春节老太太（自己做）
Every Spring Festival she (makes it herself)
# 你这是南北大菜南北结合
You are a combination of north and south dishes
# 你知道这菜叫什么菜
Do you know what this dish is called?
# 丈母娘菜
Mother-in-law dish
# 再给它抓一下 有糯米有小葱
Grab it again. There are glutinous rice and spring onions
# 你这姑爷行
You are such a good son-in-law
# 把老丈母娘做的手艺给学着了
learned the dishes from the old mother-in-law
# 农村的土菜讲究 糯米它起黏啊
The countryside dish is very particular about it’s ingredients, stick rice is very sticky.
# 不用搁别的你看这黏度上来了
No need to leave anything else, you see the viscosity is up
# 而且没有这么腻
And not so fatty
# 春节的时候做
Cook this during the Spring Festival
# 下班的时候 搁俩丸子搁点白菜
After work, put two meat balls and some cabbage
# 豆腐一炖 过去穷啊没办法啊
Stew tofu. We used to be poor and had no other choice.
# 少来点淀粉
Add less starch
# 开始炸了 四五成（油温）
Let’s start to fry 120-150 degrees Celsius (oil temperature)
# 这个烩菜有点意思了
This stew is a bit interesting
# 我觉得这烩菜 还是得白菜给它炖的
I think this braised vegetable should be stewed with cabbage
# 让它烂乎点 不能脆
Make it softer, not too crunchy
# 平常就来这么一个菜
I usually have this dish
# 一家子全解决了
The whole family is done
# 你这丸子豆腐一炸好了
Once your tofu balls are fried
# 这菜就算成功了
This dish is successfully cooked
# 不用切 手一撕就行了 手撕白菜
No need to cut, just tear it by hand, tear the cabbage by hand
# 这边先炖着 丸子也行了
Stew here first, meat balls will be done soon
# 这丸子白嘴都能吃都好吃 这大烩菜
This meatball is delicious by itself, this stew dish
# 炸豆腐
frying tofu
# 这豆腐炸的时候不用攉拢
You don’t need to move this tofu when it’s fried
# 叫它定住型就行了
Just let it form its shape
# 这时候咱给调点口
Let's make some adjustments on taste at this time
# 加点盐 两勺
Add some salt, two spoons
# 这个菜就得有点口儿
This dish has to be a bit salty
# 胡椒粉 吃出后味胡椒的辣来
The ground pepper, you can taste the spicy aftertaste of pepper
# 丸子这时候加进去
Add the balls at this time
# 团团圆圆 四季平安大烩菜
Reunion and Live well Four Seasons Stew
# 多炖会 炖个十来分钟
Simmer more, simmer for ten more minutes
# 咕咕嘟嘟 味儿就出来了
Let it simmer and the taste will come out
# 这越炖越香
The more stewed the better
# 豆腐也行了 豆腐白菜丸子 粉条
Tofu is fine too, tofu and cabbage noodles
# 大锅炖啊 这菜有食欲
Big pot stew, this dish looks so appetising
# 这菜得用砂锅出 砂锅就保温
This dish has to be made in a clay pot, it keeps the heat
# 冬天热乎 齐活
Winter makes you warm, this is all set
# 砂锅炖个十来分钟就行
Simmer in a clay pot for about ten minutes
# 熟啦 这菜有意思 看着就漂亮
It's cooked, this dish is interesting and beautiful
# 小香油来点
Some sesame oil
# 来块肉 来块丸子
Have a piece of meat and a meat ball
# 烫啊师父 您注意点
Careful it’s hot, Master, pay attention
# 吃的就是这个热乎劲
I enjoy eating this hot
# 这汤还真鲜
This soup taste really good
# 菌类跟豆腐的鲜味
The umami taste of fungus and tofu
# 这丸子好吃
This meatball is delicious
# 搁完糯米之后真是糯 而且不腻
After putting the glutinous rice, it's really sticky and not greasy
# 这冬天来一锅
Have a pot of this in the winter
# 对这个菜 就这肉香
For this dish, it's meaty
# 这个菜来一大碗米饭一吃 热乎乎的
This dish comes with a big bowl of rice and it's warm
# 我说找不着熬白菜的味
I said I can't find the taste of boiled cabbage
# 这回找着了 这黄花搭的巧
This time I found this yellow flower.
# 四季平安大烩菜
Four Seasons Ping An Stew
# 这太接地气了 老百姓太喜欢这菜了
This is quintessential home cooking. People like this dish so much.